Rafi Chowdhury

Director of Digital Strategy and Business Development - Wound Care Surgeons

Northridge, CA rafi1220@gmail.com - (901)674-4629

Seven years Marketing experience via Social Media. Recent graduate from the University of Memphis with a Bachelors of Arts in Psychology with concentration in Cognitive Science. Graduate of The LeaderShape Institute 2013. Founder/Co-founder of four start-up businesses.

Willing to relocate to: Los Angeles, CA - Memphis, TN Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Director of Digital Strategy and Business Development

Wound Care Surgeons - September 2015 to Present

Growth hacker, email marketing, project management, ergonomics, content marketing, on-page seo, offpage seo, social media, brand management, digital marketing, link building, radio advertising, business development, and much more to increase the web presence of the company and reach the target audience

- Grew Facebook page to more than 2k fans in less than 1 week
- Grew Twitter to more than 65k followers in 2 weeks
- Managed email marketing campaign of more than 50k emails

Freelancer

myCampusHacks.com - October 2014 to Present

Clients include Faithbaby, Inc., TEAM.Aero, unfunnel.com, IPS3web LLC, Easley Transportation, Beyond Steam Carpet Cleaning, Courtney Elmer, Sendoutnice.com, Pro Lock, ViAm Solutions, Healthcare Services Group, Nerium International, Senses Memphis, Pickle App, The University of Memphis, and many more

- Manage internet platforms including social media and WordPress website
- Drive traffic to site and generate sales via content marketing, on-page optimization, social media engagement, & email marketing

Co-founder & Marketer

myCampusHacks.com - August 2014 to Present

This social networking site is an up-and-coming startup focusing on improving a student's college experience

- Site received more than 150 registered users in the first month of launch
- Site was featured on several media outlets & was nominated to be featured on Inc. Magazine's "coolest college startups" for 2015

Coach chess and leadership development courses

myCampusHacks.com - August 2014 to August 2015

Chowdhury's Chess Leadership Program - Founder and Silent Owner (August 2014-August 2015)

- Coach chess and leadership development courses in Memphis schools
- · Spread the program to 8 schools locally
- The project's non-profit project, Caritas Village Chess Club was featured on ABC news in its 2nd week of launch

Founder and Owner

Chowdhury's Chocolate Checkmates - July 2014 to August 2015

Company has several active projects on chess leadership development and worked with 9 local schools

Grew company to 7 employees and is projected to generate \$12k in revenue in first year

Founder

Chowdhury's Chocolate Checkmates - June 2014 to August 2015

Manufacture chocolate chess pieces, more than 200 units were sold

Certified to manufacture and sell food due to completion of Domestic Kitchen Online Training course

Total Concept - Digital Marketing Specialist

www.ecosignsandbanners.com - February 2015 to June 2015

Leading eCommerce project www.ecosignsandbanners.com

- Extra 10,000 targeted visitors to site resulting in positive ROI within first month
- Project components encompass, but are not limited to PPC, Google Adwords, SEM, SEO, Inbound Marketing, WordPress Development, Content Marketing, Google Analytics, Heat Map, Email Marketing, B to B marketing, Sales, Google Webmaster Tools, etc.
- Site ranks of Google for multiple high competition commercial intent keywords within the digital printing industry

Digital Marketing Specialist

The Flinn Clinic - January 2015 to February 2015

Assisted with the marketing campaigns of politician George Flinn

- Built niche websites, managed and produced content for WordPress sites, created lead pages and squeeze pages, email campaigns using MailChimp, drove targeted traffic to niche sites,
- Used web analytics and marketing tools including Lead Pages, Vidlify, Fiverr.com, Click Funnels, Google Analytics, keywordtool.io, Tweepi, and Buzzsumo

Research Assistant

Mid-South Chess - 2013 to 2014

Researched under Dr. Art Graesser's lab with PhD student Brent Morgan on his dissertation on mood and multitasking

· Wrote for a Chess Intelligent Tutoring System joint venture with Brent Morgan under his company MMTech

Marketer & Tournament Director

Mid-South Chess - 2007 to 2014

Worked as head chess instructor/promoter since 2008

- Taught and promoted chess at various local schools and in the community
- Ran and organized chess tournaments both locally and nationally
- Grew the tournament to include more schools over the years
- Responsible for company's revenue growth to in excess of \$100K

Specialized Sales Clerk

Mid-South Chess - May 2013 to July 2013

Sold \$400+ worth of merchandise on any given day around the park

Leading sales representative for the company

Intern

Mid-South Chess - January 2013 to May 2013

Issued press releases, content creation, video recording of lectures, marketing, social media, and presence at lectures

Tournament Director & Vendor

Mid-South Chess - 2011 to 2012

Sold more than \$6000 worth merchandise at several single tournaments

• Ran chess tournaments consisting of more than 100 players

SOCIAL MEDIA:

Facebook: www.facebook.com/rafichowdhury.entrepreneur

Twitter: www.twitter.com/_rafichowdhury
Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/rafichowdhury

Google+: https://plus.google.com/+RafiChowdhury1406/posts

YouTube: www.youtube.com/user/RafiChowdhury1

Website: www.rafichowdhury.com - 30k unique visitors/month with Alexa Rank 100k

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Arts in Psychology

The University of Memphis May 2010 to May 2014

SKILLS

Digital Marketing (7 years), SEO (7 years), Content Management (7 years), Content Marketing (7 years), Content Strategy (7 years), Growth Hacking (7 years), Business Development (7 years), Online Marketing (7 years), Public Speaking (7 years), Marketing (7 years), Consulting (7 years), Analysis, Psychology (7 years), Negotiation (7 years), Leadership (7 years), Lead Generation, Cold Calling, Start-Ups, Client Relations, Client Management, Client Relationship Management, Wordpress, Search Engine Optimization, Typing 65 WPM, Keyboarding, Internet Research, Blogging, Blogger, Social Media, Social Media Marketing, Inventory Management, Selling, Vendor Relations, Coaching, Business Intelligence, SAAS, Analytical Skills, Google Analytics, Google Docs, Google Adwords, Google Webmaster Tools, Google+, Google Chrome

LINKS

http://chowdhurysdigital.com/

http://iviewz.com/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury-founder-of-chowdhurys-and-co-founder-of-mycampushackschowdhury/

http://meritpages.com/Rafi-Chowdhury/113766

http://mychesscoach.net/

http://noragouma.com/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury-eco-signs-and-banners/

http://paychecktopassion.com/blog/rafi-chowdhury-business-like-chess/

http://rafichowdhury.com.cutestat.com/

http://sdasia.co/2014/10/25/campus-hacks-chess-pieces-story-rafi-chowdhury/

http://start-up-booster.com/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury-great-tips-from-multiple-entrepreneur/

http://streetsideconvos.com/2014/12/17/rafi-chowdhury/

http://vintagemediagroup.com/dotcom-entrepreneur-lives-home-mama/

http://withfivequestions.blogspot.com/2015/03/meet-rafi-chowdhury-entrepreneur.html

http://www.chess.com/members/view/RafiChowdhury

http://www.dailyhelmsman.com/archives/website-aimed-to-guide-u-of-m-students-through-campus/article_c5389de1-2653-575a-8ea6-dfda0cf0e30f.html

http://www.globalyuppiestyle.com/entrepreneurial-and-life-advice-from-memphis-digital-marketing-guru-rafi

http://www.ips3web.com/online-marketing-for-your-company/

http://www.kicktraq.com/projects/1005022781/mycampushacks-social-networking-site-for-college-s/

http://www.localmemphis.com/news/local-good-news-chess-at-caritas-village

http://www.manta.com/cp/mx4snn2/547a58047a29dad011dfd7fe/chowdhury-s-chess-leadership-program

http://www.pinstopin.com/rafi-quotes/

http://www.rafichowdhury.com

http://www.rafichowdhury.com/

http://www.simandan.com/?p=14990

http://www.stephenesketzis.com/interviews/rafi-chowdhury-23-year-old-entrepreneur-digital-marketer-says-videos-infographics-and-webinars-are-the-next-big-thing/

http://www.stephenesketzis.com/interviews/rafi-chowdhury-23-year-old-entrepreneur-digital-marketer-says-videos-infographics-and-webinars-are-the-next-big-thing/

http://www.voicesofmarketing.com/written-interviews/interview-with-rafi-chowdhury/

https://plus.google.com/+RafiChowdhury1406/posts

https://twitter.com/_rafichowdhury

https://unfunnel.com/seo-keyword-strategy/

https://www.facebook.com/rafichowdhury.entrepreneur

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafichowdhury

https://www.youtube.com/user/RafiChowdhury1

AWARDS

Mid-South Psychology Conference

June 2014

Top talk of the conference with over 500 in atendence

PUBLICATIONS

The Official Website of Rafi Chowdhury

http://www.rafichowdhury.com My blog

Chowdhury's Digital

http://www.chowdhurysdigital.com Digital Consultancy Website